Hope Runs Deep
The 33 is a drama, history film directed by Patricia Riggen.
Based on the true story of the collapse of a mine in San Jose,
Chile—that left 33 miners isolated underground for 69 days.
Mario Sepúlveda, played by Antonio Banderas.
Laurence Golborne, played by Rodrigo Santoro.
Katty Valdivia, played by Kate del Castillo.
María Segovia, played by Juliette Binoche.
Jeff Hart, played by James Brolin.
Luis Urzua 'Don Lucho', played by Lou Diamond Phillips.
The 33 (Spanish: Los 33; "Los treinta y tres") is a 2015 biographical disaster-survival drama film directed by
Patricia Riggen and written by Mikko Alanne, Craig Borten, Michael Thomas, and José Rivera.
The film is based on the real events of the 2010 Copiapó mining disaster, in which 33
miners were trapped inside the San José Mine in Chile for 69 days.
The film stars Antonio Banderas as trapped miner Mario Sepúlveda.
It was released in Chile on August 6, 2015, by 20th Century Fox and in
the United States on November 13, 2015, by Warner Bros.
Pictures and Alcon Entertainment.
The film explores themes of mining, based on true
story, chile, mining accident, survival.
The tone is emotional.